WEB DESIGNER

Authoring & Design
Dreamweaver CC
Visual Studio

Digital Imaging
Photoshop CC
Illustrator CC
InDesign CC

Languages
CSS3 & LESS
HTML5
Javascript

Frameworks

Bootstrap

¡Query

Angular

JESSICA THOMAS

4255 Schirtzinger Rd. • HIlliard, Ohio 43026 • mobile: 614.893.4925 jessica.anne.thomas@gmail.com • www.jessicathomas.info

SUMMARY

Results-driven web, multimedia, and user experience designer with solid experience maintaining, updating, and designing graphics and content for high-traffic sites. Resourceful and self-directed, with meticulous attention-to-detail unwavering work ethic, and a commitment to delivering on organizational goals. Experience in wire-framing, website design, HTML, and CSS.

EXPERIENCE

Book Dog Books, Grandview Heights, Ohio (July 2012-Present) *Interactive Designer*

- Designed, coded, and supported responsive websites for multiple e-commerce sites. (www.TextbookRush.com, www.Bookstores.com, www.Fatbrain.com)
- Created marketing emails that increased click through rates by 22%.
- Improved return process through wire-framing with internal teams, better user experience and design.
- Designed promotional sweepstakes to increase site visits, sales, and mailing list subscriptions.

Blue Laser Design, Columbus, Ohio (December 2005-July 2012)

Flash/Web Designer (March 2006-July 2012),

Web Design Intern (December 2005- March 2006)

- Designed efficient, eye-catching websites from conceptualization to realization.
- Implemented jQuery scripts and flash animation to add movement and visual appeal to websites. (www.gilbertgrouprealestate.com & www.ericasata.com)
- Analyzed keywords and phrases before creating meta tags to increase website traffic by 30% (www.isaacbrant.com)
- Customized e-commerce site to enhance user experience (www.ortonceramic.infosaic17.com)
- Created custom theme on WordPress platform to reflect brand identity. (www.blog.rinkoveyecare.com)

FAMILY HEALTH, Athens, Ohio (September 2004-June 2005) *Internet Webpage Manager*

- Charged with enhancing, maintaining, and uploading content for Family Health (www.fhradio.com) and Family Medicine (www.familymedicinenews.org) sites.
- Increased traffic and daily listening statistics by launching an RSS feed to automatically download series of radio programs with easy-to-understand health information.
- Redesigned Family Medicine website to improve visual appeal and increase functionality.
- Conceptualized and designed promotional ads for placement within national magazines.

EDUCATION

OHIO UNIVERSITY, Athens, Ohio (2001-2005)

B.S. in Visual Communication, Multimedia Sequence and Minor in Business Administration